<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology and Software | Pressing Words]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.mikeleon.com/blog/categories/technology-and-software/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.mikeleon.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-30T02:42:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.mikeleon.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to boot Acronis True Image from a USB drive]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.mikeleon.com/blog/2006/11/10/how-to-boot-acronis-true-image-from-a-usb-drive/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.mikeleon.com/blog/2006/11/10/how-to-boot-acronis-true-image-from-a-usb-drive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve struggled quite a bit with this.  But I&rsquo;ve always gotten it to work.  This time I decided to save myself from future anguish by documenting the steps.  It might even save you from some extended head scratching.  Here&rsquo;s how to use a common usb key / flash drive / thumb drive to boot Acronis True Image (this was done using True Image v9.0 build 2337).  The splash screen won&rsquo;t display, but the fully functional True Image program should load just fine.  (~25MB needed)</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Make sure your BIOS supports booting from USB, and set it to do so.</p></li>
<li><p>Backup your data from the USB drive &ndash; it&rsquo;ll be wiped clean in the next step.</p></li>
<li><p>Run the &lsquo;<a href="http://h18000.www1.hp.com/support/files/serveroptions/us/download/23839.html">HP Drive Key Boot Utility</a>&rsquo; (from Windows) and format the usb drive as follows:</p></li>
</ol>


<ul>
    <li>Create New or Replace Existing Config</li>
    <li>Hard Drive</li>
    <li>Create New Filesystem</li>
    <li>Click Cancel - no need to go any further with this utility; it'll just create unneeded files which you'll want to delete - leaving just the boot loader file 'ldlinux.sys'.</li>
</ul>


<ol>
<li>Copy these two files from the True Image boot media &lsquo;Recovery Manager&rsquo; folder into the usb root directory.  (You may need to install True Image and create a bootable CD or floppy disk if you haven&rsquo;t already done so.)</li>
</ol>


<ul>
    <li> kernel.dat</li>
    <li> ramdisk.dat</li>
</ul>


<ol>
<li>Create the file &ldquo;syslinux.cfg&rdquo; in the usb root directory with the following contents:
<code> </code></li>
</ol>


<pre>
    timeout 100
    default ti9
    label ti9
        kernel kernel.dat
        append initrd=ramdisk.dat vga=788 ramdisk_size=32768 quiet</pre>


<p>That should do it.  Your USB drive should now boot into True Image.  Happy Imaging.</p>

<p>P.S. Wouldn&rsquo;t you know it, after writing all this I decided to try the latest TrueImage Home v10 (build 4,871) and guess what.  That version&rsquo;s Boot Builder creates a bootable flash drive with True Image just fine.  Thanks for fixing this Acronis!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
